mrgreen.com 2003-12-02

# Pepsi World - Privacy Policy

Pepsi-Cola Company -- Privacy Policy

The web site you have entered is operated by or on behalf of Pepsi-Cola Company ("Pepsi"), a division of PepsiCo, Inc. To learn more about Pepsi's products, click here. Pepsi is committed to protecting your personal privacy. This Privacy Policy outlines the types of information that are collected by Pepsi on its web sites, and how we use and protect it. This Policy also explains the choices that you can make about the way your information is collected and used. This Policy applies only to Pepsi web sites, and it does not apply to banners, sweepstakes and other advertisements or promotions that we may sponsor or participate in on web sites owned by third parties. 

Our Privacy Policy includes the following topics. For specific information regarding any particular topic, please click on the link below: 

* Your Consent to this Privacy Policy
* The Information We Collect
* The Way We Use Personal Information
* Collection and Use of Other Information; Use of Cookies
* With Whom We May Share Information
* Manage Your Personal Information; Unsubscribe
* Data Protection and Security
* Important Note to Kids
* Protection of Children's Personal Information
* Changes to Our Privacy Policy 
* Links to Other Web Sites
* How to Contact Us
* Applicable Web Sites
* Important Note Regarding U.S. Law

By using our web sites, you signify that you agree with the terms of our current Privacy Policy as posted on our sites as well as the terms of our Terms and Conditions. If you do not agree with any term in this Policy or our Terms and Conditions, please do not use this site or provide any Personal Information to us.

As used in this Privacy Policy, "Personal Information" means any information that is linked to your identity such as your name, street address, telephone number, screen name, age and/or email address. For information pertaining to Personal Information collected from children, click here. The site you entered may collect some or all of these types of Personal Information through a sweepstakes, contest, game, survey, questionnaire or promotion, or a registration form. Some of our web sites may require registration in order for you to participate in sweepstakes, games or other activities. In order to register on our sites, we require you to disclose your name, street address, email address, birth date and gender. Pepsi will not collect any Personal Information from your visits to our sites unless you provide your Personal Information to us voluntarily, and we will not require you to provide more information than is necessary to participate in our web sites' activities. We also do not collect financial or other sensitive data information about our users.

When you provide us with Personal Information, you are authorizing us to use that information in accordance with the terms of this Privacy Policy, which includes your right to limit our use of your Personal Information as described in this Policy.

The web site you entered may also collect Personal Information from you about a third party (e.g., the site might allow you to send an email or message to a friend, in which case we will need that person's name and email address). Please note that we use such information only for the specified purpose (e.g., to deliver the email message) and we will not contact the third party again by email unless and until the third party contacts us.

When you supply Personal Information at a Pepsi web site, we will consolidate such Personal Information and use it for the purpose for which it was collected (e.g., to enter you in a sweepstakes or to fulfill the delivery of a sweepstakes prize or product order) in accordance with the terms of this Privacy Policy. We may also use it to contact you regarding Pepsi's products or promotions as well as other products and services, which may be requested by or otherwise of interest to you (including those we may offer jointly with other companies). At any time, however, you may opt out of such future contact by unsubscribing from our database. We also use Personal Information to keep track of a user's activities on our sites, to improve our marketing and promotional efforts, to statistically analyze web site usage, to improve our web site features, design and content and to refine our marketing strategies.

We may also enhance your Personal Information by linking it to data obtained from third parties, such as non-personally identifiable information (e.g., demographic and geographic characteristics) as well as other publicly available data such as census information. Such enhanced information allows us to provide our users with a more customized experience.

Pepsi's primary goal in collecting and using Personal Information is to give you a meaningful and customized experience while you are using our web sites as well as to promote our products in a cost effective and efficient manner.

You may have heard of "cookies," which are small files or pieces of information that are stored by your browser on your computer's hard drive when you visit a web site. The use of cookies is an industry standard and you will find them at most web sites. Pepsi may use cookies to collect other information during your visit to our web sites, such as the particular site areas you visit and the activities in which you participate at our web sites. Pepsi does not automatically collect any Personal Information, but we may combine non-personal information collected automatically (through cookies) with voluntarily submitted Personal Information. Such link may occur only if you provide Pepsi with Personal Information on our sites. This practice allows Pepsi to keep track of items such as sweepstakes participation, email and advertising interaction levels, survey responses, online coupon redemption and other web activity in order to better tailor our web sites and our products to your interests and needs. Cookies may also be used to help speed up your future activities at our web sites -- the computer can remember that you have already provided Personal Information to us and not request that you provide any a second time.

Anonymous information about your computer, such as your IP address (a number assigned to your computer whenever you surf the Internet), the type of Internet browser you are using, and the type of computer operating system you are using may also be collected by us using cookies. Web servers, the computers that "serve up" web pages, automatically identify your computer by its IP address. When you request a page from this web site, our servers log your IP address.

Most browsers are initially set to accept cookies. If you'd prefer, you can set yours to refuse cookies or to alert you when cookies are being sent. Refusal of cookies at the site you entered may result in an inability to visit certain areas of the web sites or to receive personalized information when you visit the web sites.

In the course of doing business, we employ other companies to perform a variety of functions on our behalf. For example, at times we may retain third parties to analyze, update and correct data we collect on our web sites, including Personal Information, to help us improve our products, our database and our web sites. In addition, we may share Personal Information with agents, suppliers, fulfillment houses and other third parties to allow delivery of prizes, information, products or services. These suppliers and other third parties may have access to your Personal Information if it is needed to perform their functions for Pepsi, but they are not authorized by us to use your Personal Information in any way other than the intended use.

We also may share aggregate, non-personally identifiable information about our users with advertisers, business partners, sponsors, and other third parties. For example, we may tell a business partner the number of men and the number of women that entered a contest, but we do not disclose Personal Information about such contestants in violation of this Privacy Policy.

Except as stated in this Privacy Policy, we do not sell, transfer or disclose your Personal Information without your prior consent. Our intention is limit or prohibit the sharing of Personal Information provided to us in ways that are different than the ways described above without also providing you with an opportunity to "unsubscribe" or prohibit such unrelated uses.

We may also release your Personal Information if required to do so by law, or by search warrant, subpoena or court order, or to a third party to which ownership of Pepsi is transferred via an acquisition, merger, sale of assets or otherwise.

You are ultimately in control of the Personal Information that we collect and use. We want to keep your data complete, up to date and accurate. Pepsi provides its users with the following options to manage their Personal Information that is in reasonably retrievable form in our database: 

  * Send us an email: Send an email to [webmaster@pepsi.com](mailto:webmaster@pepsi.com). Be sure to include your name, username and clear instructions regarding any change to your Personal Information or if you would like us to unsubscribe you from our database. 
  * Send us mail or call us: Send us your request via the mail. Be sure to include your name, username and clear instructions regarding any change to your Personal Information or if you would like us to unsubscribe you from our database. Send to: Pepsiworld, 1999 Bryan Street, Suite 2420, Dallas, Texas 75201 or call us at 1-800-960-3602. 
  * Online management: Visit the "Join Pepsi", "Manage Your Profile" or similar section of the site where you can manage your Personal Information and/or subscribe to or unsubscribe from our database. 

In the event that a user unsubscribes from our database, we will retain a record of the Personal Information and the unsubscribe action for our internal records as evidence of the action and our compliance with this Privacy Policy.

We take commercially reasonable precautions to keep your Personal Information secure. All access to the information we collect is subject to physical, electronic and managerial restrictions to prevent unauthorized access, modification or misuse. Notwithstanding the foregoing, we cannot guarantee the security of any information you disclose online, and you do so at your own risk.

Before providing your name, address, email address or any other personal information to anyone on the Internet, be sure to ask your parents permission.

Pepsi is committed to protecting the online privacy of children and making the Internet safe for our users. It is our policy to prohibit users from registering on our sites or otherwise submitting Personal Information to us except with express permission from their parent/guardian. We encourage parents/guardians of children under 13 to regularly check and monitor their children's use of email and other activities on line.

Please note that everything in this section and elsewhere in this notice about Pepsi's information collection and usage practices regarding children under 13 applies only to Personal Information about a child under 13, which is specifically the information we collect and can trace back to a specific child. If the information we collect is anonymous or combined as aggregate information, so that we cannot "match up" the child to their Personal Information, then this children's policy does not apply. You should assume, however, that all Personal Information we collect is tracked on an individual basis unless you are informed otherwise on the website. 

  * . In order for a user to register on our site, we initially require the following information: 
    * Password
    * Email address
    * Birth date
  
If the Birth date entry reveals the child is under the age of 13, we freeze the information the child has provided and we request the email address information of the child's parent/guardian so that we can obtain consent from the parent/guardian. The information the child provides will not be used in any way until we receive authorization from the parent/guardian. After the parent/guardian grants permission for the child's registration, this information will then be used in accordance with this Privacy Policy. 
  * . As stated above, children under the age of 13 will be requested to provide the parent/guardian's email address. At that time, an email will be sent by Pepsi to the parent/guardian explaining that the child is attempting to register on the site. Pepsi will provide the parent/guardian with the site's URL and the child's user name and password in order for the parent/guardian to access the child's information. Once entered into the site, the parent/guardian will have the opportunity to:
    1. Review and submit the child's Personal Information to Pepsi (including child's and parent/guardian's name, email address, postal address and birth date) 
    2. Edit the child's Personal Information
    3. Delete the child's Personal Information
  
A follow up email message will be sent to the parent/guardian approximately 3 to 5 days after the parent/guardian has submitted the child's registration information to Pepsi. This second email is used by Pepsi to obtain verification from the parent/guardian of their permission to submit the child's Personal Information and register the child on the Pepsi site. In addition to the email, Pepsi will send the parent/guardian a letter or postcard notifying them of the child's registration. The information contained in this letter is similar to the information contained in the email but does not require a response from the parent/guardian. The child's Pepsi registration will be activated once the parent/guardian visits the website and submits or edits the child's information as described above. When a parent/guardian submits the child's registration information, an email is sent to the child notifying them that this has happened and making them eligible to participate in site activities.  

  * . After the parent/guardian grants permission pursuant to the above process, the child's information will then be used in accordance with this Privacy Policy whenever that child attempts to enter a sweepstakes or engage in other activities on the web site. We will not use the parent's email or postal address for any purpose other than to communicate with the parent in order to obtain permission for their child to register and participate on our web sites, and we will retain the parent's information for our internal records as evidence of our compliance with this Privacy Policy.  

  * . Once the Personal Information of a child is submitted and entered into our database, as the parent/guardian of a child, you are always free to verify or change the Personal Information we have in our database pertaining to that child. Please be aware that for security reasons the parent/guardian must provide Pepsi with the child's user name, password and email address needed to access the child's information. To verify or change the child's Personal Information, please see "Manage Your Personal Information; Unsubscribe". 

Changes to Our Privacy Policy  
Pepsi reserves the right to change or remove this Privacy Policy at our discretion. We will post any changes to this Policy or any new policy here and we encourage you to visit this area frequently to stay informed. If there is any material change in the type of information we collect or way in which we use such information, then we will obtain your permission before we make any such change.

Users should be aware that when you are on this web site you could be directed to other sites that are beyond our control. There may be links to other web sites that include links from advertisers, sponsors, and partners that may use the Pepsi family of brand or logos. These other web sites may send their own cookies to users, or otherwise collect data or solicit Personal Information. Always be aware of where you are surfing on the Web. Check the linked site to locate and review its privacy policy, which may be different from this Privacy Policy. Pepsi does not endorse and makes no guarantee or representation as to the sufficiency, accuracy or completeness of the content or privacy policy of any third-party web site to which you may be linked from this site.

Should you have any questions or concerns about this Privacy Policy or the collection of information, please email us at: [webmaster@pepsi.com](mailto:webmaster@pepsi.com) or call us at 1-800-960-3602.

This Privacy Policy applies to the following web sites:  
www.pepsi.com; www.pepsione.com; www.dietpepsi.com; www.mountaindew.com; www.codered.com; www.fruitworks.com; www.sierramist.com; www.mugrootbeer.com; www.mrgreen.com; www.pepsitwist.com; www.wildcherrypepsi.com; www.aquafina.com; www.pepsiblue.com; www.aquafinaessentials.com; www.ampenergy.com, and others that may be added in the future.

Please note: The laws and regulations in different countries impose different (and even conflicting) requirements on the Internet and data protection. We are located in the USA, as are the servers that make this site available worldwide. All matters relating to this site are governed by the laws of the State of New York in the USA. If you are located in the European Economic Area and you contact us, please note that any information you provide will be transferred to the USA and by submitting the information you authorize this transfer.
